AHSANSHAHID

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER



ahsandev.work@gmail.com



https://ahsan-sha.github.io/Portfolio/



6622780776



181 Gilla Dr Ballwin, MO



SUMMARY

Ahsan is a Senior Full Stack Web Developer with well over 12 years of professional experience in developing web applications and beautiful websites from scratch. He has a Bachelor of Computer Science from University of Toronto. His journey as a web developer has been impressive and he continues to grow and learn every day. Ali is a great fit for any start up or web agency, with his range of skills he has the ability to take on any size project or client and deliver a product or website that meets today's web standards and expectations.



EDUCATION

University of Arkansas

BS in Computer Sciences September 2011 - April 2013



CERTIFICATION

- · Zend Certified PHP Engineer
- Microsoft Certified Specialist with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript
- Adobe Certified Expert

PROFILE

I'm seeking a full time, challenging and creative role as a Full Stack Web Developer at a company who can benefit from the 10 years of experience I gained at some well-known companies across the states. In my next role I would like to take on more responsibility and work towards being in a position where I might be able to manage a small team while continuing to learn and grow as a Full Stack Web Developer.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Web Application Development • Software Engineering • Computer Information Systems

Beck-End & Front-End Development • Single-Webpage Application • Database Development

Advanced Coding • Troubleshooting & Debugging • Testing & Analysis • Solution Design

Leadership • Communication • Adaptability • Teamwork • Problem Solving • Goal-Oriented

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

- Knowledge of OOP / Design Patterns
- Expert in PHP, Proficient in MVC
- Web Services, API, JSON, XML

DATABASES

- Relational Databases
 MySQL, SQL
- NoSQL Databases
 MongoDB

WEB RELATED

- WordPress, Shopify, React, jQuery
- Larave, VueJS, HTML5, CSS3, AJAX
- Bootstrap, AnimateJS, BounceJS.

METHODOLOGIES:

Agile, Scrum

FRAMEWORKS

- Laravel, VueJS, Codelgniter, Symphony,
- CMS / Ecommerce Systems (WordPress,
- OpenCart, Shopify, Big-Commerce)

LANGUAGES

• PHP, JavaScript, HTML

SERVER SOFTWARE

- Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS)
- LAMP, XAMPP, Apache
- SSH, cPanel, FTP

SOFTWARES

- Git (Github, GitLab, BitBucket)
- PhpStorm, Visual Studio Code, Sublime
- Photoshop, XD, Illustrator, Sketch, InDesign

WORK EXPERIENCE

PX MEDIA INC

SENIOR FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Reno, NV Sep 2019 - July 2022

Overview: Working as a Full Stack Developer, Worked on different PHP WordPress, custom and MVC frameworks including Shopify, Codeignitor, Laravel. While on front-end I have used React and vueJS as a JavaScript frameworks and CSS, CSS3, SASS and bootstrap for styling. I use to work remotely for this company. 4 to 5 developer was under me in my team and i was leading them as team lead. I worked as Senior full stack developer for helping them out, also i was managing the projects too as a project Manager.

Environment: React, VueJS, Javascript, JSON, HTML5, CSS3, WordPress, Laravel, Bootstrap, Shopify, PHP, AJAX Google Maps, Photoshop, Git, Agile, Webpack, RESTful API's, Jest/Enzyme.



INSPIRED MEDIA GROUP

BACKEND DEVELOPER (WORDPRESS FOCUSED)

Reno, NV May 2016 - August 2019

Overview: Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues. Discussed project progress with customers, collected feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns. Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans. Delivered performance-driven and user-centric websites that met all business requirements. Developed custom WordPress plugins using PHP, Javascript and CSS. Manage back-end services and interchange of data between server and user, including server-side logic and database integration. Coordinated weekly team meeting with all WordPress engineers. Maintain GIT repositories and Pantheon environments. Responsible for translating designs and concepts into highly usable and engaging web applications using a variety of technologies.

Environment: PHP, JavaScript/JQuery, AJAX, MySQL, JSON, HTML, CSS, Google Maps, Photoshop, Git, Scrum.

CLIMAX MEDIA

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Toronto, ON June 2013 - April 2016

Overview: I started my career working at Climax Media because I wanted to learn from an agency who has a track record going above and beyond. I was given an opportunity to work on some amazing well-known brands. As a Frontend developer at Climax, my roll was to creating landing pages in HTML, Bootstrap, CSS and JavaScript with animations. Also XD, Figma and PSD into HTML or Bootstrap conversions. In that company i got opportunity to learn PHP and work on Backend side.

Environment: PHP, HTML, Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery.

REFERENCE

Available on Request